Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Notice Period: 1 Month

Engineering]

# Prakash Vemuri ( Featured

Software Engineer III seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, JEE, Spring Boot, MySQL, Mongo DB, Elastic Search, JPA, Hibernate, Apache Kafka



Current Designation: Software Engineer 3 Java J2EE

Current Company: Factset Research Systems

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Secunderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer III, Application Programming, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Java, JEE, Spring Boot, MySQL, MongoDB, JPA, Hibernate, Apache Kafka, Core

Java, Maven, TDD, GIT, JUnit, Mockito, Sonar, IntelliJ Idea, Design Patterns

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

### Summary

Passionate Java developer having 5 years of experience in building REST backend systems on both monolithic and micro services architectures with strong object oriented programming skills.

Currently working as Java backend professional at FactSet Research Systems, Hyderabad.

Experienced in Java Technologies and bulding REST based APIs using Spring Boot and Mircroservices.

Sound Knowledge on RDBMS and NoSQL databases.

Good understanding on applying Design Patterns and TDD.

### Work Experience

Factset Research Systems as Software Engineer 3 Java J2EE

May 2018 to Till Date

Software Engineer III, Developing REST backend systems for Factset's Wealth Product.

Software Engineer II, Developed REST APIs on top of Financial Data.

Next Sphere Technologies as Software Engineer I

Oct 2015 to May 2018

Software Engineer I, Developed MLM Product on microservices architecture.

Associate Software Engineer, Started as native Android and REST API backend developer.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Java SE 7

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
JAVA	8
TypeScript	2.7
SPRING MVC	
RESTful Web-services	
Apache Tomcat	8
Windows 10,8,7,XP, Ubuntu, Mac OS X	
IntelliJ IDEA, STS, Eclipse, NetBeans	
Visual Studio Code	4
MAVEN	3
Tortoise SVN	
JUnit, Spring Test Module, Mockito	
gradle	3
WEBPACK	3
JEE	8
JSE	8
JavaScript	
Angular	4
JSON	
spring boot	
GIT	

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Tamil	Beginner			
Telugu	Expert			

## **Projects**

Project Title: Wealth Management Product

Client: Factset Research Systems Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Hyderbad

Role: Sr. Programmer

Skill Used: Java, J2Ee, Spring Boot, Microservices, Hibernate

Role Description: Developing REST backend systems on the product development

Duration: May 2018 - Oct 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 10

Project Details: This product will give wealth advisory firms a quick way to build up a presence in the internet to interact with their clients by showing client's portfolio analytics data on the portal with the performance of their portfolios how they are behaving.

- -> Owned designing and developing entire REST backend on top of portfolio analytics data.
- -> Learnt and worked on the Pentaho ETL tool to load the clients user and portfolio data into MySQL DB.
- -> Worked on writing complex SQL queries to perform analytics on portfolio returns, allocations, performance, asset wise.
- -> Developed the platform for importing and exposing user base for wealth advisers and wealth investors.
- -> All APIs are documented with Swagger.
- -> Wrote 100% coverage unit test cases for all the APIs which is integrated with SONAR code quality tool.

Project Title: TITAN

Client: Forever Living International Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 30 Role: Sr. Programmer

Skill Used: MicroServices, Java 8, Spring Boot, RESTful Sevices, Angular 2, MySQL 5.7, Alfresco CMS, Apache kafka

Queue, Docker

Role Description: Part of core development team on building Payment micrservice Service which Supports US, Europe, Asia Markets with Workdpay,paypal processors, Hands on experience on Credit/Debit card Tokenization and Card payments. Worked on building Modern REST APIs

Duration: May 2017 - May 2018

Project Details: Titan - An online Health care Products Store. This Platform is a software suite of products to build and operate the multi level marketing(MLM) business which is built from the ground up using MicroService based Architecture. It is a cluster of portals having independent microservices each like Shoping Sites, Stores, Product Catalogs, Customer Management, Order Management, Content management (CMS), Single Sign On (SSO), Payment Systems in world wide markets.

Project Title: rapid! PayCard,

Client: Unirush LLC

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2016 - Jun 2017 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Chennai

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Spring REST, Ionic 1, Angular 2, JWT, MS SQL Server, RESTful Services, Hibernate, JPA.

Role Description: Part of Code Dev Team from scratch to Deployment on Client Systems UAT and Production Environments.

Owned Full Backend Development on Architecture and building REST back End Systems

Build Security Module - Authentication Systems with JWT Standard

Project Details: Rapid Pay Card is a Hybrid Mobile Application which helps in enrollment of payment cards with the Systems

from the

Employees in the Unites States. App with Single Code Base and Deployed on Multiple Platforms- Android, iOS, Windows, Web App and allows to enroll Pay Cards instantly light weight fast on the fly. Added Features as locate ATMs in United States, User Account Processing, Image Processing, Consent Form Upload and Download.

Project Title: office BOT Client: NextSphere

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2015 - May 2016

Project Location: chennai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Android Framework, JAVA 8, Asp.Net WEB Api 2, Angular 2, IIS 8, Active Directory, RESTful Services, MongoDB, Role Description: Started as Mobile Developer, Designed and Developed End-to-End App and placed in play Store Worked on developing REST Back End Systems applying Object Oriented Programming Concepts and REST Principles Built Android Notifications, Help Screen Overlay

Project Details: Office BOT is an In-house Native Android App built as a Product which helps to give access to organisational Activities such as

Leave management, Employees hierarchy Chart, News Feed, Appraisal Review, Time Sheet Management, Notifications, employee Communication, Peer Appreciations, Project Allocations and Sprint task Tracking.

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

**Work Authorization**